<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Deep Learning | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/deep-learning/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/deep-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Deep Learning</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/deep-learning/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python or Java. What is better to choose for studying?</title>
      <link>https://example.com/project/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/project/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know what you might be thinking – why do we need to talk about Java or Python separately? Why not go straight to the general comparison of Python vs Java? In fact, the reason is quite simple. This kind of brief overview will be useful for both beginners and more experienced programmers. How? Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are already far advanced in the field of programming, you may not feel like you are doing most of the work on the machine, without even thinking about it. That is why it would be a great idea to go through the very basics – this will allow you to refresh your knowledge, and to some extent test them. Although, of course, this approach will be most useful for novice programmers. In this case, they will not only be able to find out which language is better in general terms, but also which one is best suited for them. This is a winning situation for everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s start our comparison of Python or Java with a brief overview of Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;python&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python was created by Guido van Rossum and was first introduced to the general public in 1993. It is an interpreted, high-level programming language, by the way, object-oriented from and to. In fact, all this has become the reason why this language has become one of the most popular in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A high-level programming language (among other things) focuses its attention on simplicity. Python&amp;rsquo;s entire design philosophy is based on readability – the language uses spaces and has a very simple syntax to accomplish its tasks. It has become widely known precisely because it is considered to be one of the easiest programming languages to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of its description, namely “object-oriented&amp;quot; is very important. OOP or object-oriented programming is a form of programming philosophy that focuses on objects and data, instead of the logic needed for management. Inheritance, polymorphism, and encapsulation are just a few of the basic functions that define object-oriented programming. Why are OOP languages popular? Among other factors, which we will talk about later, OOP makes it easier to maintain the code and allows programmers to reuse it for other, separate projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for usage, Python was originally created as a Linux development language, but since then it has become widespread in the field of web development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These were some basic facts about Python – they should help you lay down a fundamental understanding of the language and contribute to making a choice when choosing Python or Java. This is just one side of the coin – next, let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;java&#34;&gt;Java.&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java was created at the same time as Python, but already by James Gosling and two of his colleagues. And, yes, that&amp;rsquo;s right, its logo really shows a cup of coffee, since the name itself was taken from the coffee brand of the same name. Finally, we managed to tell you about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If readability is the first thing that comes to mind when we talk about Python, Java also has its own associations. In this case, it is an acronym for WORA. WORA means “Write Once, Run Everywhere&amp;quot; – this is the slogan by which Java has become known and is related to the most notable feature of the programming language. Java is universal – as the slogan says, it can be run on any platform and with any application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java was developed based on C and C++. It was a kind of strategic maneuver, since these were the most popular programming languages of the 90s and the learning curve was much easier for those who already knew how to use C and C++. Although Java was not as “pure” as Python, it was created as an OPP language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Java is most popular in Android application development and companies with large amounts of data. Considering this, for our comparison of Java or Python, these two languages do not pose a particular threat to each other&amp;rsquo;s fields of application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, you already know about programming languages from the opposition of Python or Java. However, to consolidate the information, let&amp;rsquo;s briefly discuss the differences between Java and Python.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;python-or-java--the-main-differences&#34;&gt;Python Or Java – The Main Differences&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the first differences when choosing Python or Java is speed. Java is faster than Python, this is an indisputable fact. However, it is worth noting that this is applicable only for certain projects – today modern processors are able to compensate for this disadvantage of slow programming languages. Although even with that said, Java is considered the fastest of the two. The main reason for this is that Python is an interpreted language and defines the data type at runtime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another difference in the confrontation between Python vs Java is the difference in the very process of writing code. Java requires you to write long and more complex lines of code, whereas Python is very short and requires a minimal amount of code. Moreover, Java requires you to specify the type of variables you want to use, whereas Python (being dynamically typed) does not require this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are just a few technical differences in the Python Java format. As soon as we choose between Java and Python in the next section, we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about less technical things. So let&amp;rsquo;s continue answering the question “Should I learn Python or Java?” with the definition of criteria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;comparison-criteria&#34;&gt;Comparison Criteria&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Correct comparison criteria are very important when analyzing two programming languages – if we want to know which language is better, Python or Java, we must define the criteria. There are many aspects that we can discuss, but to be honest, it will be almost impossible to address them all in this guide. For this reason, we have chosen only the most common and interesting aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our comparison, we will use three key criteria – ease of use, popularity and possible salary. Let&amp;rsquo;s briefly talk about each of them and find out which of them is worth choosing Python or Java, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;ease-of-use&#34;&gt;Ease Of Use&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people, when looking for programming languages to learn, prefer simpler and less time-consuming languages. The situation may be reversed if you have already mastered several other programming languages, but for a beginner, the most important thing is to get into the world of programming as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that industry veterans disagree with this approach, novice developers prefer simpler languages. You may also disagree with such a decision, but competition in the labor market clearly has a huge impact on this fact. Since this area is very popular now, several candidates can apply for one position. That is why people want to finish their studies as soon as possible in order to start gaining experience and qualify for higher-paying positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;popularity&#34;&gt;Popularity&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the popularity of programming languages may seem somewhat relative, this is actually a very important aspect if we choose Python or Java. Firstly, the programming community does not like to waste time learning “supposedly working” and inefficient languages. That is why, if the language is popular, then you can be sure that this popularity has its own reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, individual communities support the programming language they are interested in in various ways. Actively participating in discussions, answering questions, or even creating training materials – all these things can be incredibly useful. If you decide to learn a programming language with such support, then you will never feel a shortage of any sources for learning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;salary&#34;&gt;Salary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And, of course, wages. To be honest, most likely this is the first thing people think about and it is what motivates them to learn a programming language. It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that programmers earn good money – the field of information technology is actually one of the most profitable in the whole world!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although it is worth considering one important aspect. Different programming languages have different indicators of average wages. In comparison with Python Java, this difference is also present – if in your opinion this factor is very significant, then you should pay special attention to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;comparison&#34;&gt;Comparison&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we will be able to answer the question, which is better to choose Python or Java. Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about each of these factors in turn. Let&amp;rsquo;s start with ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;which-language-is-easier-to-use&#34;&gt;Which Language Is Easier To Use?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Python&amp;rsquo;s reputation as “incredibly easy to use&amp;quot; speaks for itself. Of course, Java cannot be called a complex programming language, but in comparison with Python, everything is much simpler and, well &amp;hellip; more readable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;which-language-is-more-popular&#34;&gt;Which Language Is More Popular?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it comes to popularity, then whichever language we take, Python or Java, they are both very popular in the programming world. It is quite difficult to choose only one, more popular, since they serve for different purposes. If Java is used and appreciated in the application development environment, then Python&amp;rsquo;s position is strong among web developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, one thing is for sure – both of these programming languages have their own huge and dedicated communities with a lot of different content throughout the network. If you decide to start learning any of them, then you won&amp;rsquo;t have to experience any problems with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;which-language-has-the-best-salary&#34;&gt;Which Language Has The Best Salary?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Glassdoor.com , the average annual salary of a Java developer is estimated at $88,100 USD. This is about $7340 USD per month. The same source provides data on the salaries of Python developers. He estimates the average of their salaries at $92,000 USD per year or almost $7670 USD per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you understand, the difference is not very big. Even though Python developers get a little more than their Java counterparts, both figures are much higher than average.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At the moment you already know the difference between Java and Python, but the main question is still open – should you learn Java or Python? As you understand, both languages are quite similar in what they offer to their users. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s Python or Java, you can be sure that you will have a huge community behind you, and many new opportunities will open up before you. It all depends on your goals:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If web development seems interesting to you, then you can start learning Python.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;However, if you are more attracted to application development, then Java will be an excellent alternative.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, we are close to completing our Python or Java tutorial. By this point, you should have a complete understanding of the basic aspects of these languages, their advantages and disadvantages. Whichever language you choose, we wish you good luck!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
