<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>开源 | Academic</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tag/%E5%BC%80%E6%BA%90/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://example.com/tag/%E5%BC%80%E6%BA%90/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>开源</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://example.com/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>开源</title>
      <link>https://example.com/tag/%E5%BC%80%E6%BA%90/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>My lask week (28.05-04.06)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/last-week-04.06.22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/last-week-04.06.22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last week I managed to publish 2 posts on my website thanks to the Hugo statistics generator. ** You can view them by going to the messages section.**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also managed to do two lab work on the topic &amp;ldquo;Operating systems&amp;rdquo;: Tools for creating applications in UNIX OS and Named pipes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pros and cons of being a programmer</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/%D0%BF%D0%BB%D1%8E%D1%81%D1%8B-%D0%B8-%D0%BC%D0%B8%D0%BD%D1%83%D1%81%D1%8B-%D0%B1%D1%8B%D1%82%D1%8C-%D0%BF%D1%80%D0%BE%D0%B3%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%BC%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%81%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%BC/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/%D0%BF%D0%BB%D1%8E%D1%81%D1%8B-%D0%B8-%D0%BC%D0%B8%D0%BD%D1%83%D1%81%D1%8B-%D0%B1%D1%8B%D1%82%D1%8C-%D0%BF%D1%80%D0%BE%D0%B3%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%BC%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%81%D1%82%D0%BE%D0%BC/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;Advantages&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constant work on self-improvement, knowledge of your tao, the way of a warrior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with very advanced people, meeting with colleagues who understand you perfectly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work at normal computers, in a harmless environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participation in the life of the country — &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo;, not &amp;ldquo;TV&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The opportunity to earn as much as you like, if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to — downshift.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Permanent professional conferences, seminars, meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a high probability of changing several countries of residence and continents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The probability of living an interesting and long life, because a loaded brain ages more slowly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is always an opportunity to retrain, to teach someone. Even in retirement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a rule, a positive outlook on the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;disadvantages&#34;&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The need for the first time, almost 2-3 years, to be at a tedious job or to be picked up in a large team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constant inactivity, which you need to fight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Problems with blood circulation and nerves in the fourth decade of life. Dry eye syndrome can overtake in two to three years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Difficulty in choosing worthy managers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The risk of making a mistake in choosing a subject area that you will devote considerable time to studying.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fixed costs for upgrading the computer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changing the subject area can lead to a return to the starting point of a career.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Condemnation and misunderstanding of others when communicating on topics close to programming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;bottom-line&#34;&gt;Bottom line&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our virtues are a continuation of our shortcomings, but the virtues are so weighty that they will be enough for more than one good career.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My last week (14.05-21.05)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/last-week-28.05.22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/last-week-28.05.22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last week I managed to publish 2 posts on my website thanks to the Hugo statistics generator. ** You can view them by going to the messages section.**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also managed to do two laboratory work on the topic &amp;ldquo;Operating systems&amp;rdquo;: Programming in the UNIX OS command processor. Advanced programming and Programming in the UNIX OS command processor. Branching and loops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific programming languages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/%D1%8F%D0%B7%D1%8B%D0%BA%D0%B8-%D0%BD%D0%B0%D1%83%D1%87%D0%BD%D0%BE%D0%B3%D0%BE-%D0%BF%D1%80%D0%BE%D0%B3%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%BC%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%80%D0%BE%D0%B2%D0%B0%D0%BD%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/%D1%8F%D0%B7%D1%8B%D0%BA%D0%B8-%D0%BD%D0%B0%D1%83%D1%87%D0%BD%D0%BE%D0%B3%D0%BE-%D0%BF%D1%80%D0%BE%D0%B3%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%BC%D0%BC%D0%B8%D1%80%D0%BE%D0%B2%D0%B0%D0%BD%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scientific programming is a highly oriented programming style for scientific calculations. It is distinguished from other types of programming by the extreme correctness and stability of the final product, the strict separation of the scientific and interface parts, the individuality of algorithms, as well as the predominance of efficiency over versatility.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific programming is at the heart of any modern global research. All advanced technologies — from quantum computers to space programs — would be impossible without specialists in the field of scientific programming, able to provide scientists with a reliable and accurate tool for making discoveries.
A number of branches of science directly depend on the level of development of scientific programming. So, unmanned vehicles, &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; control systems for urban and agricultural management, stock exchanges are waiting for their execution; robotics, genetic engineering, artificial intelligence that surpasses human capabilities are waiting for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;specializations&#34;&gt;Specializations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists use various programming languages, the choice of which depends on the type of task and the preferences of the author. Historically, the first high-level programming language is Fortran, it has written many well-established libraries of mathematical statistics and libraries for solving differential equations, which is relevant for economics and biology, respectively.
Python has a simpler syntax, which is also suitable for programming mathematical calculations. Python is used for data processing in mathematics, physics, economics, biology, chemistry and is able to work with some other &amp;ldquo;scientific&amp;rdquo; languages: Fortran, C++, C#.
In turn, C# allows programming on the platform.NET, adapt the program to the common language runtime environment (CLR) and accelerate development in the framework of operational scientific sessions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** Great news - from a huge variety of activities, a programmer-scientist has the opportunity to choose exactly what best suits his abilities and at the same time proceed in this choice only from personal preferences.** Let &amp;rsquo;s list the main types:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ALGORITHMS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search, sorting, encryption, error detection in communication systems. This area will always attract the greatest attention to the practicality of the problems being solved;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES AND COMPILERS.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also includes the optimization of existing analogues. This is quite a creative and researchable niche, although the peak of its popularity is already passing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything that lies on the verge of fiction: text, image and voice recognition, semantic text analysis, self-learning neural networks and neural network programming as one of the most attractive and promising areas. It is this area that can offer maximum surprises;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SUPERCOMPUTER AND QUANTUM THEORY&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a complex of tasks and concepts that are still beyond our technological and intellectual capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MULTICORE SYSTEMS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development of the concept of accelerating the operation of systems through parallel multi-threaded programming. This area is rapidly gaining momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ROBOTS and PRODUCTION AUTOMATION.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is a purely practical sphere, directly related to the industrial use of software developments, and therefore the most mastered since the 80s of the last century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CREATION OF VIRTUAL REALITY SYSTEMS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s where psychology and programming intersect most tightly. Ideally, work in this direction can bear fruit in the form of the emergence of new training systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SYSTEM MODELING (CAD/CAM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engineering discipline, whose specialists are in high demand for solving problems of purely practical communication tasks, and it does not matter whether it is network communication, gas pipe or water supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COMPUTER GRAPHICS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solves an urgent range of issues related to developments in the field of accelerating graphics processing in computer systems, as well as improving color rendering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;** Programming moves science, which moves technological progress. Inventions that were considered revolutionary yesterday serve everyday needs in the XXI century: Microwave oven, mobile phone, 8-bit home computer. It depends on the programmer-scientist which peaks science will reach today and which of them will enter every home tomorrow.**
&lt;strong&gt;In the hands of a programmer-scientist there are tools not only for the development of industry, but also for improving the overall quality of life. Such a specialist increases the prognostic function of humanity, helping to anticipate and prevent climatic, financial, humanitarian disasters.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easy markup languages</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/%D0%BE%D0%B1-%D0%BB%D0%B5%D0%B3%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D0%B5%D1%81%D0%BD%D1%8B%D1%85-%D1%8F%D0%B7%D1%8B%D0%BA%D0%B0%D1%85-%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%B7%D0%BC%D0%B5%D1%82%D0%BA%D0%B8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/%D0%BE%D0%B1-%D0%BB%D0%B5%D0%B3%D0%BA%D0%BE%D0%B2%D0%B5%D1%81%D0%BD%D1%8B%D1%85-%D1%8F%D0%B7%D1%8B%D0%BA%D0%B0%D1%85-%D1%80%D0%B0%D0%B7%D0%BC%D0%B5%D1%82%D0%BA%D0%B8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-markup-language&#34;&gt;What is a &amp;ldquo;markup language&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markup language&lt;/strong&gt; is a set of codes that, when applied to plain text, allows you to add one or more of the following properties (among others):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define the text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structure the text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe the layout of the text&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decorate the text
One markup language you encounter every day (unless you&amp;rsquo;re a hermit) is hypertext markup language, or HTML. Websites and apps that bring you news and show you your email are built, at least in part, with HTML markup using tags as a mechanism to mark up raw text content. For example, consider the following HTML fragment:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;body&gt; &lt;h1&gt;Introducing HTML&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here is a paragraph in HTML... we know it&#39;s a &lt;strong&gt;paragraph&lt;/strong&gt; because the surrounding \&lt;p\&gt; tags define it as one.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/body&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the &amp;ldquo;p&amp;rdquo; tag indicates that all subsequent text, up to the closing &lt;/p&gt; tag, is a paragraph. In this sense, it defines the text as a paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But pay attention also to the &amp;ldquo;body&amp;rdquo; tags&amp;hellip; they often serve to determine the layout of a web page, for example, how many fields are on the side of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the &amp;ldquo;strong&amp;rdquo; tags will decorate the word &amp;ldquo;paragraph&amp;rdquo; in bold, and the &amp;ldquo;h1&amp;rdquo; tags can both mark up the title (separate it from the surrounding text) and define a larger font.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with some markup languages (among them HTML) is that entering these tags manually is a very tedious task. And with other languages like XML, tags and their attributes make up more of the overall content than the text itself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;enter-a-lightweight-markup-language&#34;&gt;Enter a lightweight markup language&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wanted to take advantage of markup languages, for example by publishing an HTML page on the internet or converting a DocBook file to PDF so that it could be printed, you had to do one of two things. On the one hand, you can spend time learning these languages inside and out, writing them down manually, and then checking your work three times. Or you could invest the money in a tool that manages the complexity of them for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, some enterprising developers have come up with a third option. They created new markup languages that contained many (in some cases most or all) of the functions of heavier analogues, but greatly simplified the syntax. These &amp;ldquo;light&amp;rdquo; languages include the familiar Markdown as well as Asciidoc, the Egc format in Org mode and the Mediawiki syntax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;lightweight-markup-languages-have-a-simple-syntax&#34;&gt;Lightweight markup languages have a simple syntax&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the distinguishing features of these languages is that their &amp;ldquo;tags&amp;rdquo; (such as they are) should be intuitive. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the previous fragment, this time written in Asciidoc:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Introducing Asciidoc &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; Where are the &lt;em&gt;paragraph&lt;/em&gt; tags? We dont need them&amp;hellip; Asciidoc is smart enough to realize this is a paragraph!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much more readable, no? Starting from the top, we can identify the title, since it is &amp;ldquo;underlined&amp;rdquo; with strokes. You could do this if you were writing by hand, just draw an underscore under the page title in notepad. There are also no paragraph tags — Asciidoc treats anything between two empty lines that don&amp;rsquo;t have any other markup on them as &amp;ldquo;plain&amp;rdquo; paragraph text. Finally, the asterisks around the word &amp;ldquo;paragraph&amp;rdquo; are indicated in bold. Raise your hand if you did it in a text message to mean the same thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each has one or more corresponding processors
Heavy-weight markup languages usually have a special application for their interpretation. On the Internet, your browser and, possibly, a web server will turn the code into bright web pages. For documents in XML format, it can be something like Microsoft Word, which reads and writes in DOCX format. (this is another XML dialect). This way you will never have to interact directly with the source of these documents, only the cute facades that your applications show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, documents written in light languages are read by a person in their original form (another tenant), but only true nerds can consider them beautiful. To get a good result, you need to use a processor. These are applications that will consistently go through your markup and transform it into something else that looks good. The same projects that develop the language itself, as a rule, create a utility for its use. The Markdown project offers a Perl script with the same name, and the accompanying Asciidoc program is written in Python. In addition, other conversion utilities will include support for some of these languages. One such example is the excellent Pandoc, which will use Markdown, as well as lightweight tagging, restructured text, Mediawiki and Org-Mode and convert them to PDF, DOCX, ODT and others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;asciidoc-markdown-pandoc-formats&#34;&gt;Asciidoc markdown Pandoc formats&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, lightweight markup languages allow you to work with plain text, the most portable data format on the planet, but in the end they still give a beautiful result. Now that you are convinced of its merits, which language to choose? Markdown is undoubtedly the most popular and has its advantages (more on this later). But Asciidoc, in particular, is a worthy alternative. In the next section, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at a few reasons why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;comparison-of-markdown-and-asciidoc&#34;&gt;Comparison of Markdown and Asciidoc&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Asciidoc format was created to simplify DocBook, one of the most common formats when writing long (especially technical) texts. One of the requirements for fame is that it is a one-on-one translation, that is, for each element in the DocBook there is a corresponding representation in Asciidoc. Below we will look at some pros and cons of Asciidoc compared to Markdown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;asciidoc-covers-a-superset-of-written-elements&#34;&gt;Asciidoc covers a superset of written elements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of Markdown from the very beginning was to create a simple format for web writers. Thus, the entry elements it supports (at least the original implementation, see below) are aimed at automating the more time-consuming aspects of HTML writing (lists, for example, that require &lt;ol&gt; or &lt;ul&gt; tags in addition to &lt;li&gt; tags for each element).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;complex-asciidoc-markdown-formats&#34;&gt;Complex asciidoc markdown formats&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asciidoc also contains them, but also offers more advanced DocBook elements, such as warnings (for example, &amp;ldquo;Note:&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Info:&amp;rdquo; callout blocks) and complex table layouts. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you have to use them all the time, but they will be there and available if you ever need them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;asciidoc-is-a-single-format&#34;&gt;Asciidoc is a single format&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the popularity of Markdown began to decline, some of its users began to face some of the disadvantages described above. So these users started developing their own extensions to solve these problems, such as the ability to add tables or footnotes/notes. Soon, many &amp;ldquo;flavors&amp;rdquo; of Markdown appeared, including (among others):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flavor used by Github for the &amp;ldquo;Readme&amp;rdquo; files of the projects it hosted.
An &amp;ldquo;extended&amp;rdquo; version based on the PHP port of the original Markdown, with additional HTML-related features.
A fragrance called &amp;ldquo;MultiMarkdown&amp;rdquo;, which implements many functions of writing longer forms, including citations, definitions and cross-references.
As a result, your document may require elements that are not all covered by the same flavor. In contrast, Asciidoc does not suffer from the same fragmentation as Markdown currently does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;asciidoc-is-aimed-at-a-variety-of-publishing-styles&#34;&gt;Asciidoc is aimed at a variety of publishing styles&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is great for quickly getting a blog post out of your head and onto the page. But out of the box it is not designed to structure longer works like a book. Asciidoc is designed for this, and one example is its &amp;ldquo;enable&amp;rdquo; functions. These operators allow you to include the entire contents of one file in another:
include::somefile.adoc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not much different from how basic documents work in text editors. This allows, for example, to compose each chapter as a separate file, and then &amp;ldquo;include&amp;rdquo; them all in one file representing the book. When you process this &amp;ldquo;book file&amp;rdquo;, the result will be as if all the chapters were written directly into this document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#Markdown is enough for most users&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown covers all the basics for most users. For those who are just looking for a blog or printing some notes in text format, Markdown supports all the elements they will need. Cross-references mean little to a user who just wants to create a simple note or web page. You could even use Markdown for longer works with simple layouts like roman&amp;quot; and combine them yourself at the end.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My last week (01.05-07.05)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/last-week-14.05.22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/last-week-14.05.22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last week I managed to publish 2 posts on my website thanks to the Hugo statistical website generator. &lt;strong&gt;You can see them by going to the post section.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also managed to do two laboratory work on the subject of &amp;ldquo;Operating Systems&amp;rdquo;: The Midnight Commander command shell and the VI Text Editor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My last week (07.05-14.05)</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/last-week-21.05.22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/last-week-21.05.22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last week I managed to publish 2 posts on my website thanks to the Hugo statistics generator. ** You can view them by going to the messages section.**&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also managed to do two laboratory work on the topic &amp;ldquo;Operating systems&amp;rdquo;: Programming in the UNIX OS command processor. Command files and emacs Text Editor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The design of the report in Markdown</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/%D0%BE%D1%84%D0%BE%D1%80%D0%BC%D0%BB%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%B5-%D0%BE%D1%82%D1%87%D0%B5%D1%82%D0%B0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/%D0%BE%D1%84%D0%BE%D1%80%D0%BC%D0%BB%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%B5-%D0%BE%D1%82%D1%87%D0%B5%D1%82%D0%B0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This document is intended to familiarize the user with the functionality of the Markdown markup language.
Markdown is a lightweight markup language that is a tool for converting code to HTML.
The main feature of this language is the simplest syntax, which serves to simplify writing and reading markup code, which, in turn, makes it easy to correct it.
Now let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at the functions of the Markdown markup language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown is not a replacement for HTML. The Markdown syntax is quite limited, and corresponds to only a small subset of HTML elements. It includes the following elements:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Block elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#Parag&#34;&gt;Paragraphs and Line Breaks&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#Headers&#34;&gt;Headers&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#Blockquotes&#34;&gt;Quotes&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#Lists&#34;&gt;Lists&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#CodeBlocks&#34;&gt;Code Blocks&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#Lines&#34;&gt;Horizontal (dividing) lines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lowercase elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#Links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#Emphasis&#34;&gt;Text Selection&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#Code&#34;&gt;Code fragments of strings&lt;/a&gt;;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#Images&#34;&gt;Images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Additional elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Backslash](#Backslash Escapes);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Automatic Links](#Automatic Links);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#SpecialSymbol&#34;&gt;HTML Special Characters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information about the listed functions, see the section &amp;ldquo;Syntax Description&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;syntax-description&#34;&gt;SYNTAX DESCRIPTION&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;block-elements&#34;&gt;Block elements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-nameparaga-paragraphs-and-line-breaks&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;Parag&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Paragraphs and line breaks&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to create a paragraph using the syntax of the Markdown language, it is enough to separate the lines of text with one (or more) empty line (any line that contains nothing but spaces and tab characters is considered empty).
In order to insert a visible line break (the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br/&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; element), you must end the line with two spaces and press the &amp;ldquo;Enter&amp;rdquo; key.
Many elements of the Markdown syntax look and work much better when they are formatted using &amp;ldquo;hard line translation&amp;rdquo; (line separation performed by the user himself, and not by the program automatically). Such elements include quotes, lists, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-nameheadersa-headings&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;Headers&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Headings&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Markdown markup language supports 2 styles of heading designations: underlining and highlighting with a symbol (&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;).
Headings are highlighted using underscores with equal signs (&amp;quot;=&amp;quot;) if the title is of the first level, and hyphens (&amp;quot;-&amp;quot;) if the title is of the second level. The number of underscores is not limited.
When selecting headers using the symbol (&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;), from one to six of these characters are used, which are set at the beginning of the line (before the header). In this case, the number of characters corresponds to the header level. In addition, it is possible to provide the title with closing characters (&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;), although this is not mandatory. The number of closing characters does not have to match the number of initial characters. The level of the title is determined by the number of initial characters.
The headings of the first and second levels, made using underscores, look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-level-header&#34;&gt;First level header&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;second-level-header&#34;&gt;Second level header&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The headers of the first, third and sixth levels, made using the symbol (&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;), look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-header-of-the-first-level&#34;&gt;The header of the first level&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;third-level-header&#34;&gt;Third level header&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;sixth-level-header&#34;&gt;Sixth level header&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above headings made with the symbol (&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;) are identical to the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-level-header-1&#34;&gt;First level header&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;third-level-header-1&#34;&gt;Third level header&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;sixth-level-header-1&#34;&gt;Sixth level header&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, the following is displayed on the screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-level-header-2&#34;&gt;First level header&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;second-level-header-1&#34;&gt;Second level header&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;first-level-header-3&#34;&gt;First level header&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;third-level-header-2&#34;&gt;Third level header&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h6 id=&#34;sixth-level-header-2&#34;&gt;Sixth level header&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-nameblockquotesa-quotes&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;Blockquotes&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Quotes&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Markdown language uses the &amp;ldquo;more&amp;rdquo; (&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;quot;) sign to indicate quotations. It can be inserted both before each line of the quotation, and only before the first line of the paragraph.
Also, the Markdown syntax allows you to create nested quotes (quotes inside quotes). Additional levels of citation marks (&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;quot;) are used to mark them.
Quotes in Markdown can contain all kinds of markup elements.
Quotes in the Markdown language look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an example quote,
in which
an angle bracket is placed before each line &amp;gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an example quote,
in which the angle bracket
it is put only before the beginning of a new paragraph.
The second paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embedding a quote into a quote looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First Citation level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second level of citation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third level of citation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First Citation level
As a result, the following is displayed on the screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an example quote,
in which before each line
an angle bracket is placed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an example of a quote
in which an angle bracket
is placed just before the beginning of a new paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enclosed quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First Citation level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second level of citation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third Citation Level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First Citation Level&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The citation level cannot exceed the 15th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-namelistsa-lists&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;Lists&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Lists&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown supports ordered (numbered) and unordered (unnumbered) lists.
Markers such as asterisks, pluses, and hyphens are used to form unordered lists. All the listed markers can be used interchangeably.
To form ordered lists, numbers with a dot are used as markers. An important feature in this case is that the numbers themselves, with which the list is formed, are not important, since they do not affect the output HTML code. No matter how the user numbers the list, the output will in any case have an ordered list starting with one (1, 2, 3 &amp;hellip;). This feature should be taken into account when it is necessary to use the ordinal numbers of the elements in the list so that they correspond to the numbers obtained in HTML.
Ordered lists should always start with one. List markers usually start from the beginning of the line, however, they can be shifted, but not more than 3 spaces. The marker must be followed by a space or a tab character.
If necessary, you can insert a quote into the list. In this case, the citation notation (&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;quot; ) should be indented.
The ordered lists look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explorer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semiconductor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dielectric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unordered lists look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explorer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semiconductor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dielectric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guide&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semiconductor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dielectric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explorer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semiconductor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dielectric
The output of all three listed options has the same result.
As a result, the following is displayed on the screen:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explorer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semiconductor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dielectric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explorer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semiconductor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dielectric&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quote inserted into the list looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A list item with a quote:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a quote
inside the list item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second item of the list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, the following is displayed on the screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A list item with a quote:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a quote
inside the list item.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second item of the list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When inserting quotes into the list items, it is important to keep in mind that the list items must be on the same level, and quotes must be indented. If the rule with a single list level is not followed, the next item in the list after the quote will be automatically numbered with the digit &amp;ldquo;1.&amp;rdquo;
In addition, if necessary, you can insert the source code into the list. In this case, it should be written with double indentation – 8 spaces or 2 tab characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A list item containing the source code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;source code &gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-namecodeblocksa-code-blocks&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;CodeBlocks&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Code blocks&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Formatted code blocks are used when it is necessary to quote the source code of programs or markup.
To create a block of code in the Markdown language, it is necessary to start each line of a paragraph with an indent consisting of four spaces or one tab character. The code block continues until there is a line without indentation (or the end of the text). Inside the code block, ampersands (&amp;quot;&amp;amp;&amp;quot;) and angle brackets (&amp;quot;&amp;lt;&amp;quot; and &amp;ldquo;&amp;gt;&amp;rdquo;) are automatically converted into HTML markup elements. In addition, it should be noted that inside the code blocks, the usual Markdown syntax is not processed.
The code block in Markdown looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a regular paragraph:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a block of code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-namelines-a-horizontal-lines-separators&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;Lines&#34;&gt; &lt;/a&gt; Horizontal lines (separators)&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to create a horizontal line using the Markdown syntax, you need to place three (or more)a hyphen or asterisk on a separate line of text. It is possible to place spaces between them.
Horizontal lines in Markdown look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the text to be divided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of the text that needs to be divided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the text to be divided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of the text that needs to be divided
As a result, the following is displayed on the screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the text to be divided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part of the text that needs to be divided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When using this tool, it is important to remember that an empty line must be left after the first part of the text and before the second. This rule must be observed only when using hyphens. If it is not followed, the second-level header and a line of plain text will be displayed on the screen. When using the asterisk symbol, this rule can be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lowercase-elements&#34;&gt;Lowercase elements&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h5 id=&#34;a-namelinksa-links&#34;&gt;&lt;a name=&#34;Links&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Links&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Markdown supports two styles of link design:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hyperlink, with immediate indication of the address (in-text);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A hyperlink similar to a footnote.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is assumed that in addition to the URL, there is also a link text. It is enclosed in square brackets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My last week</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/last-week-07.05.22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/last-week-07.05.22/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last week I managed to launch my website thanks to the Hugo statistical website generator. And he&amp;rsquo;s right in front of your eyes! &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cool, isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I also managed to do two laboratory work on the subject of &amp;ldquo;Operating systems&amp;rdquo;: The basics of the interface of user interaction with the Unix system at the command line level and working with reports in Markdown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-template-is-mobile-first-with-a-responsive-design-to-ensure-that-your-site-looks-stunning-on-every-device&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-started&#34;&gt;Get Started&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👉 &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/templates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a new site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personalize your site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💬 &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chat with the &lt;strong&gt;Wowchemy community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugo community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🐦 Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/wowchemy&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@wowchemy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GeorgeCushen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;@GeorgeCushen&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/search?q=%23MadeWithWowchemy&amp;amp;src=typed_query&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;#MadeWithWowchemy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💡 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Request a &lt;strong&gt;feature&lt;/strong&gt; or report a &lt;strong&gt;bug&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;em&gt;Wowchemy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⬆️ &lt;strong&gt;Updating Wowchemy?&lt;/strong&gt; View the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/hugo-tutorials/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Update Tutorial&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crowd-funded-open-source-software&#34;&gt;Crowd-funded open-source software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help us develop this template and software sustainably under the MIT license, we ask all individuals and businesses that use it to help support its ongoing maintenance and development via sponsorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-click-here-to-become-a-sponsor-and-help-support-wowchemys-future-httpswowchemycomplans&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/plans/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;❤️ Click here to become a sponsor and help support Wowchemy&amp;rsquo;s future ❤️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a token of appreciation for sponsoring, you can &lt;strong&gt;unlock &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/plans/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; awesome rewards and extra features 🦄✨&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/hugo-academic-cli&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugo Academic CLI&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Automatically import publications from BibTeX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Check out the latest &lt;strong&gt;demo&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/user-stories/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;view the &lt;strong&gt;showcase&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; of personal, project, and business sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page builder&lt;/strong&gt; - Create &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/page-builder/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;widgets&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;elements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit any type of content&lt;/strong&gt; - Blog posts, publications, talks, slides, projects, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create content&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/content/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/import/jupyter/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jupyter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/install-locally/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin System&lt;/strong&gt; - Fully customizable &lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/customization/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font themes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display Code and Math&lt;/strong&gt; - Code highlighting and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;LaTeX math&lt;/a&gt; supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrations&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Disqus commenting&lt;/a&gt;, Maps, Contact Forms, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beautiful Site&lt;/strong&gt; - Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry-Leading SEO&lt;/strong&gt; - Help get your website found on search engines and social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Galleries&lt;/strong&gt; - Display your images and videos with captions in a customizable gallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Friendly&lt;/strong&gt; - Look amazing on every screen with a mobile friendly version of your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-language&lt;/strong&gt; - 34+ language packs including English, 中文, and Português&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-user&lt;/strong&gt; - Each author gets their own profile page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Pack&lt;/strong&gt; - Assists with GDPR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Out&lt;/strong&gt; - Bring your site to life with animation, parallax backgrounds, and scroll effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Click Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; - No servers. No databases. Only files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wowchemy and its templates come with &lt;strong&gt;automatic day (light) and night (dark) mode&lt;/strong&gt; built-in. Alternatively, visitors can choose their preferred mode - click the moon icon in the top right of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt; to see it in action! Day/night mode can also be disabled by the site admin in &lt;code&gt;params.toml&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://wowchemy.com/docs/customization&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Choose a stunning &lt;strong&gt;theme&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for your site. Themes are fully customizable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version control. Git.</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/about-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/about-git/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-the-version-control-system&#34;&gt;About the version control system&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is a &amp;ldquo;version control system&amp;rdquo; and why is it important? A version control system is a system that records changes to a file or set of files over time and allows you to return later to a specific version. For file version control, this book will use the source code of the software as an example, although in fact you can use version control for almost any type of file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a graphic or web designer and you want to save every version of an image or layout (most likely you will), the version control system (hereinafter referred to as SLE) — just what you need. It allows you to return files to the state they were in before the changes, return the project to its original state, see the changes, see who last changed something and caused the problem, who set the task and when, and much more. Using SLE also means in general that if you have broken something or lost files, you can safely fix everything. In addition to everything, you will get it all without any extra effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;local-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Local version control systems&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people use copying files to a separate directory as a version control method (perhaps even a directory with a time stamp, if they are smart enough). This approach is very common because of its simplicity, but it is incredibly prone to errors. You can easily forget which directory you are in and accidentally change the wrong file or copy the wrong files that you wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to solve this problem, programmers have long ago developed local SLE with a simple database that stores records of all changes in files, thereby monitoring revisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most popular SLE was the RCS system, which is still distributed with many computers today. RCS stores on disk sets of patches (differences between files) in a special format, using which it can recreate the state of each file at a given time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;centralized-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Centralized version control systems&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next major problem that people face is the need to interact with other developers. In order to deal with it, centralized version control systems (CSCs) were developed. Systems such as CVS, Subversion, and Perforce use a single server containing all versions of files, and a number of clients that receive files from this centralized repository. The use of CSCS has been the standard for many years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach has many advantages, especially over local SLE. For example, all project developers know to a certain extent what each of them is doing. Administrators have full control over who can do what, and it is much easier to administer the CSCS than to operate local databases on each client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite this, this approach also has serious disadvantages. The most obvious disadvantage is a single point of failure represented by a centralized server. If this server goes down for an hour, then during this time no one will be able to use version control to save the changes they are working on, and no one will be able to share these changes with other developers. If the hard disk on which the central database is stored is damaged, and there are no timely backups, you will lose everything — the entire history of the project, not counting single repository snapshots that have been saved on local developer machines. Local SLE suffer from the same problem: when the entire project history is stored in one place, you risk losing everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;distributed-version-control-systems&#34;&gt;Distributed version control systems&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where distributed version control systems (RCS) come into play. In RSKV (such as Git, Mercurial, Bazaar or Darcs), clients do not just download a snapshot of all files (the state of files at a certain point in time) — they completely copy the repository. In this case, if one of the servers through which the developers exchanged data dies, any client repository can be copied to another server to continue working. Each copy of the repository is a complete backup of all data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, many RSCs can simultaneously interact with several remote repositories, thanks to this you can work with different groups of people using different approaches at the same time within the same project. This allows you to apply several approaches to development at once, for example, hierarchical models, which is completely impossible in centralized systems.&lt;/p&gt;
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-template-is-mobile-first-with-a-responsive-design-to-ensure-that-your-site-looks-stunning-on-every-device&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/wowchemy/wowchemy-hugo-modules/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      The template is mobile first with a responsive design to ensure that your site looks stunning on every device.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
